SOHRAB HUSSAIN

id.sohrabhussain@gmail.com | +971-507467251 | Dubai, UAE

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic technical professional with complete understanding of entire software development lifecycle. 10+ years of experience in developing mobile applications using Objective C/Swift & React Native. Proficient in Objective C, JavaScript, TypeScript language standards, Object Oriented Programming and Application Life Cycle.

SKILLS

- Mobile App Development
- IOS, React Native
- TypeScript, JavaScript, HMTL, Swift, Objective C,
- Agile Development
- Testing and maintenance
- App Center & Codepush
- Firebase Analytics, Realtime
 Database & Remote Config
- AppStore/Google PlayStore
- Mongo DB, GraphQL
- Apple Pay, Google Pay

- XCode, WebStorm, VS Code, Xamarin Studio, Android Studio
- SOAP/REST, XML/JSON Services
- Google Maps APIs, GeoJSON
- APNS & FCM Services
- GitLab, SourceTree, POST Man
- TFS, Agile process
- NPM, Yarn
- Azure DevOps, Codemagic
- Redux
- IBM Mobile First

WORK HISTORY

SR. FULLSTACK DEVELOPER / RAQMIYAT LLC - Dubai / 08.2020 - Current

- Started working in IBM Mobile First Platform.
- Responsible to write adapters in MFP for backend and React Native for front end.
- Integrating services to the existing application.

- Started React Native development in order to meet the client's requirements.
- Adapting the application to new requirements, as necessary.

- Establishing a detailed program specification through discussion with clients.
- Introduced agile methodologies and effective development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces using knowledge of serial communications and database design to improve user experience.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / HCL INFOSYSTEMS LTD / 09.2013 - 09.2015

- Involved at every project phase, from concept creation to app store deployment.
- Client communication so as to understand client's requirement.
- Providing sales team with estimation of upcoming new projects.
- Designing of images and documentation of projects.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / VAYAM TECHNOLOGIES LTD - Delhi, Delhi / 02.2011 - 02.2013

- Optimizing the applications for ensuring maximum performance.
- Doing coding for a variety of mobile applications for iOS devices.
- Worked with customers for needs analysis, proposal development and vendor costs to produce competitive estimates.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.

EDUCATION

SYMBIOSYS UNIVERSITY

POST-GRADUATION DIPLOMA: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

UTTAR PRADESH TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLY: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified Scrum Master, ScrumAlliance - 2021

PROJECTS

AJMAN ONE, ADG

https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/ajmanone/id1163528416

This application is the window for citizens, residents and visitors to the emirate of Ajman, through it you can access:

Government services:

Accessing the services of government entities in the Emirate of Ajman, through its various digital channels, and reviewing the various tenders that are offered to private companies and establishments.

Bills Payment:

The application provides a variety of electronic payment methods, as well as paying bills for water, electricity, telecom and other services. It also informs users about exchange offices and ATMs locations throughout the emirate of Ajman.

Health:

The application provides knowledge about pharmacies, hospitals and clinics in the emirate of Ajman, and ways to reach them through the application of Google Maps.

Education:

The (Ajman One) application includes an education window, allowing users to learn about public and private schools, universities, institutes and nurseries, in the emirate of Ajman.

Land and real estate:

If you want to rent a house or buy land, that is easy, as the application informs you about real estate offices, their locations and their opening times.

Transportation:

You can renew vehicle license, reserve parking via text messages, and learn about petrol stations and vehicle maintenance workshops in the emirate of Ajman.

SIMSARI, ERES

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/simsari/id1441243917?ls=1&mt=8

Simsari is an enterprise, authenticated and trusted Multiple Listing Service (MLS) portal that regulates real estate brokers and enables them to establish contractual offers. Simsari initiated by Dubai Land Department (DLD) and Real Estate Regulatory Authority (RERA) and developed by Emirates Real Estate Solutions (ERES) as a response to the growing demand for a trusted and regulated MLS in the real estate market. Through Simsari, buyer brokers can search for property listings, where they can find their perfect match properties and secure them instantly through Simsari's brokerage network. As well, seller brokers can list their properties and complete the transactions themselves. This revolution in smart real estate transactions is available only through Simsari

DUBAI REST, DUBAILAND DEPARTMENT

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dubai-rest/id1437805105?mt=8

Dubai REST includes certificates of owned properties (To whom it may concern), title deeds; property valuations, and map requests, as well as filing first instance lawsuits, filing disputes for amicable settlements, lawsuit inquiries, a Rental Good-Conduct Certificate, requests to register and renew Ejari Contracts, a rental increase calculator, Ejari contract cancellations, project status tracking service, and real estate services trustees.

HiHome, HiHome Pvt. Ltd.

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hihome/id1540775004

With this application customer can select, order and receive your order at your doorsteps with few taps. HiHome is gathering all different types of food that you and your family are looking for, whether you are craving appetizers, main courses or desserts, you will find them all in our menu.

Why HiHome?

Pay online or in cash

Track your order from start to finish

App available in Arabic and English

Unique design that allows you to enjoy your purchase experience Find exclusive deals

HiHome (Sellers), HiHome Pvt. Ltd.

https://apps.apple.com/us/app/hihome-sellers/id1533685850

HiHome is a unique experience that allows home entrepreneurs to operate their business from home without much effort with better chance to get exposed to extra broader customer base. HiHome attract customers by ensuring smooth shopping experience and prompt delivery.

Ejari Contracts, a rental increase calculator, Ejari contract cancellations, project status tracking service, and real estate services trustees.